# MUSTHAK AHAMED, B.Sc (Hons.) QUANTITY SURVEYOR / COST MANAGER

™ musthakahamedd@gmail.com

+94764723264



# **PROFESSIONAL PROFILE**

I am a Self-motivated and Resourceful Quantity Surveyor having technical and commercial knowledge working in Qatar and Sri Lanka. I have mixed experience of multiple roles and tasks around 5 years working in the Construction industry with a full range of both Pre and post Contract activities. I am specializing in the field of Water Transmission & Distribution pipe line projects, building construction, Irrigation infrastructure and road projects. Competent in commercial, cost, and financial management knowledge, as well as strong numerical, communication, and negotiation skills to manage projects by ensuring contractual requirements, are fulfilled and the project objectives are achieved. I am enthusiastic about my profession, work well in a team and am a quick learner.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Jan 2021 – Aug 2023 OATAR

# QUANTITY SURVEYOR (Sacyr Construccion)

#### **PRE-CONTRACT CORE RESPONSIBILITIES**

- Receiving pre contract documents from client and understanding the nature of work
- Taking quantities from received drawings and preparing BOQ or if BOQ provided confirming the BOQ quantities with drawings and identifying the extra works if any
- · Subcontractors Quotations based rate analyzing
- Preparing Comparison reports for the Quotations
- · Assisting with the preparation of tender documentations
- Tender Submissions

#### **POST-CONTRACT CORE RESPONSIBILITIES**

- Preparation of Interim Payment Application (IPA)
- Negotiate & follow with consultant to get timely certification of interim payment application within the period stipulated by the contract
- · Evaluating & certifying subcontractor payments
- Identifying, Preparation and submission of Variations
- Preparation of rate breakups for varies items
- · Measurement for payment purpose
- · Maintain day works records and material on site report
- · Preparation of claims & evaluation of extension time
- Assist with compilation of as built drawings.

Jan 2020 - Nov 2020 SRILANKA

# QUANTITY SURVEYOR (RIFTHY GROUP & CONSTRUCTION)

Project: School Building Development Projects in Srilanka

#### **PRE-CONTRACT CORE RESPONSIBILITIES**

- Taking quantities from received drawings and preparing BOQ
- Study the approved for construction drawing, specification, Bill of Quantities and prepare all materials requirements.
- Dealing with Sub-contractors, Suppliers and floating inquires and follow up for quotations
- Quotations based on Rate analysis with Subcontractors & suppliers
- Preparing Comparison reports for the Quotations
- Calculate the cost of complete a project and preparing cost report

#### **POST-CONTRACT CORE RESPONSIBILITIES**

- Preparing interim payment applications
- Negotiate & follow up with clients to get a timely certification of an interim payment application
- Reporting on cost variance based on contract scope, contractual requirement, direct & indirect cost assessment, cost allocation for material & analysis of budget vs. actual
- Identify, and timely issuing of notices of cost/time impact due to changes & preparation of variation claims with all detail backups
- · Preparation of additional claims extension of time
- Taking off individual measurements for civil & MEP works

Jan 2019 - Dec 2019 SRILANKA

# SITE SUPERVISOR & TRAINEE QUANTITY SURVEYOR (MEGA CITY CONSTRUCTION)

Project: Urban Development Authority - 672 Housing Units Projects

#### **DUTIES & RESPONSIBILITIES**

- Be present at the site of the works
- Responsible for all technical works. In addition, controls the laborers and conducts the construction works
- · Measure and taking of quantities of works done
- Observe the progress of works and compare with the work plan
- Inform the reginal engineer of any occurrence in the development of the works, affecting positively or negatively the quality and timely completion of the works
- Perform tests, under guidance and instructions of the testing department.
- Perform any other duty related with the supervision of works, as instructed by the reginal engineer
- Responsible for communication between parties such as labors and superiors, safety control and workers welfare.

# **PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATIONS:**

# BSc (Hons) in Quantity Surveying & Commerical Managment (R)

Birmingham City University - UK (2024)

### **Higher National Diploma in Quantity Surveying**

United Kingdom Associaton of Professionals - UK (2018 -2020)

## **Advanced Diploma in Management Accounting**

Chartered Institute of Management Accountants (CIMA) (2022)

### Computer Aided Designing and Drafting (CADD), Auto CAD 2D&3D

College of Pebbles in Sri-lanka (2017)

### Diploma in computer studies

British informatics of Computer Technology MS Office Packages (MS Word & MS Excel), Operating System,Internet & E-mail (2016)

# **PROFESSIONAL SKILLS**

- FIDIC, ICTAD (Sri Lanka) and method of measurement such as CESMM3, POMI, SMM7, Sri Lankan SMM SLS- 573
- · Ability to read and assess Architectural & Structural drawings
- · Have gained competence and hand on experience on AutoCAD
- Effective communication skills when dealing with clients, developers, consultants, and elected representatives
- · Having natural driven with loyal, strong, and proactive work ethic
- · Ability to deliver effective presentations
- Skill at analyzing and interpreting information
- · Proven motivational and leadership skills

# **COMPUTER LITERACY**

- AutoCAD
- PlanSwift
- · MS Office

# **PERSONAL DETAILS**

Name in Full :Fowzul Jameel Musthak Ahamed

Nationality :Sri lankan Marital Status :Single Driving License :Sri lanka Passport :N8161906

I hereby confirm that the particulars furnished by me are true and correct to the best of my knowledge.

Yours faithfully

#### **Musthak Ahamed**